A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA386b
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon
1910-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA386b
1 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Arrangement note
The project files are arranged in series according to country. Each country or geographical area was assigned a three-digit number by RF staff. In addition, letters signifying program areas are used: for example, "A" indicates a grant in the Medical Sciences, and "C" Nursing. Material is organized within these letter/program subdivisions alphabetically by grant title. A grant title usually consists of a heading that includes the name of the institution or individual that received the grant. Thus each grant, or project, is filed individually in one or more folders.
File Plan note
RG 1.1, 1.2, and part of 1.3
Organization of the Rockefeller Foundation's archives:
RG 1 Projects
RG 2 General Correspondence
RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy
RG 4 China Medical Board
RG 5 International Health Board/Division
RG 6 Field Offices
RG 7 Treasurer's Office
RG 8 Comptroller
RG 9 Personnel
RG 10 Fellowships
RG 11 Information Services
RG 12 Diaries
RG 13 Oral Histories
RG 14 Counsel
RG 15 Secretary
RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions
RG 17 Dockets
RG 18 Declinations (100F)
RG 19 Non-textual Materials
RG 20 Communications Office
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Confidential material in this record group has been segregated and is inaccessible. Each pertinent file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material within each file is not necessary. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact a RAC archivist.
Other Finding Aids note
Other available finding aids describing Rockefeller Foundation records, projects include:
FA387 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.2
FA388 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.3
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: project files.
Humanities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Humanities; Hospitals; Hookworm disease; Medical sciences; Medical care; Malaria; Life sciences; Nursing; Public health; Public health administration; Epidemiology; Diseases; Arts; Agriculture; Philanthropy; Yellow fever; Natural history; Yaws; War relief; Viruses -- Research; Tuberculosis; Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Scholarships; Scarlatina -- Hospitals -- Administration; Respiratory organs -- Diseases; Public health -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
- Latin America, 1936-1961; 300; 3.2 Cubic Feet; 8 __Boxes __3.2 cubic feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of material relating to more than one country in Latin America. Most of the series is composed of files of recipients of Foundation Agricultural Scholarships in the 1950's (300 D).
  Arrangement note
  Five subseries as follows:
  300 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  300 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  300 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  300 R Humanities and arts
  300 S Social sciences
  - Medical Education Survey, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Medical Libraries - Handbook Distribution, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Medical Library Survey - Cunningham, Eileen R., 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Surgery Teaching - Survey, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agricultural Scholarships, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Scholarships, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Scholarships, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Aguilar Ch., Ismael - Arca B., Manuel), 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Arias Segura, Carlos Luis - Botacio, Joaquin Jr.), 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Cabrera Iporre, Maximo - Cassalett Davilla, Climaco), 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Chamorro Mera, Rosendo A. - Coelho, Antonio S.), 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Coelho, Jose C. - Cordero Villaba, Angel), 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Coronel Kautz, Manuel - Donoso, Augusto), 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Elias, Jose - Fernandez Oreamuno, Joaquin E.), 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Galindo Alonso, Jorge - Gallo, Jose R.), 1951, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Gaspar, Adalberto - Gonzalez Avila, Pedro M.), 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Itto, Minaro - Latino Ruiz, Mario), 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Lizarraga Herrera, Joaquin H. - Maroni, Vasco), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Martinez Salazar, Eugenio - Martins de Souza, Ubirajara R.), 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Meyrer, Paulo H. - Mora Urpi, Jorge E.), 1953-1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Mora Rostran, Jose - Morales Bermundez, Marciano), 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Nieto Hatem, Jorge - Ortega Castro, Jacobo), 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Pacitti, Sylas Oswaldo - Paterniani, Ernesto), 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Patino Mendez, Graciano - Pereira, Fernando C.), 1952-1958 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Pereira, Marcos Ruy - Pineda Lacayo, Laureano), 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Postigo, Rosendo - Rabaj Campos, Serafin), 1951-1958 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Ramirez Castano, Amalia - Ravines, Hugo Martin), 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Reyes Casteneda, Pedro - Rondon Olazabal, Mario), 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Ruschel, Renao - Russi Stampfli, Enrique), 1951-1952, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Salazar, Angel - Scaletzky, Jayme), 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Scheuch Hernandez, Friedrich - Urquidi M., Rene), 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Vargas Guzman, Edgard - Villena Duchen, Willy), 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Wetzel, Clovis Terra - Zelaya Quintero, Ronald), 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Medical Exam. Reports A-M), 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 0035A)
  - Agricultural Scholarships - (Medical Exam. Reports N-Z), 1951-1957 (Box 6, Folder 0035B)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Animal Husbandry, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Animal Husbandry, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Animal Husbandry - Reports, 1949, 1951; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Electron Microscopy, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Exchange of Personnel, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Economics and Rural Life, 1949-1950, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Librarians' Meeting, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Inter-American Society of Soils Scientists, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Pan American Congress of Agronomy, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Cultural Relations Survey, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Latin American Survey - Brickell, Herschel, 1949-1953 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Economics, Development of - (Fetter, Frank), 1941 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Latin America - Medical Sciences, 300.A
    - Medical Education Survey, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Medical Libraries - Handbook Distribution, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Medical Library Survey - Cunningham, Eileen R., 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Surgery Teaching - Survey, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Latin America - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 300.D
    - Agricultural Scholarships, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Agricultural Scholarships, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Agricultural Scholarships, 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Aguilar Ch., Ismael - Arca B., Manuel), 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Arias Segura, Carlos Luis - Botacio, Joaquin Jr.), 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Cabrera Iporre, Maximo - Cassalett Davilla, Climaco), 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Chamorro Mera, Rosendo A. - Coelho, Antonio S.), 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Coelho, Jose C. - Cordero Villaba, Angel), 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Coronel Kautz, Manuel - Donoso, Augusto), 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Elias, Jose - Fernandez Oreamuno, Joaquin E.), 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Galindo Alonso, Jorge - Gallo, Jose R.), 1951, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Gaspar, Adalberto - Gonzalez Avila, Pedro M.), 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Itto, Minaro - Latino Ruiz, Mario), 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Lizarraga Herrera, Joaquin H. - Maroni, Vasco), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Martinez Salazar, Eugenio - Martins de Souza, Ubirajara R.), 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Meyrer, Paulo H. - Mora Urpi, Jorge E.), 1953-1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Mora Rostran, Jose - Morales Bermundez, Marciano), 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Nieto Hatem, Jorge - Ortega Castro, Jacobo), 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Pacitti, Sylas Oswaldo - Paterniani, Ernesto), 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Patino Mendez, Graciano - Pereira, Fernando C.), 1952-1958 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Pereira, Marcos Ruy - Pineda Lacayo, Laureano), 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Postigo, Rosendo - Rabaj Campos, Serafin), 1951-1958 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Ramirez Castano, Amalia - Ravines, Hugo Martin), 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Reyes Casteneda, Pedro - Rondon Olazabal, Mario), 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Ruschel, Renao - Russi Stampfli, Enrique), 1951-1952, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Salazar, Angel - Scaletzky, Jayme), 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Scheuch Hernandez, Friedrich - Urquidi M., Rene), 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Vargas Guzman, Edgard - Villena Duchen, Willy), 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Wetzel, Clovis Terra - Zelaya Quintero, Ronald), 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Medical Exam. Reports A-M), 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 0035A)
    - Agricultural Scholarships - (Medical Exam. Reports N-Z), 1951-1957 (Box 6, Folder 0035B)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Agriculture, 1938, 1941-1947, 1951-1964 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Animal Husbandry, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Animal Husbandry, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Animal Husbandry - Reports, 1949, 1951; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Electron Microscopy, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Exchange of Personnel, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Economics and Rural Life, 1949-1950, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences - Librarians' Meeting, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Inter-American Society of Soils Scientists, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Pan American Congress of Agronomy, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Latin America - Humanities and Arts, 300.R
    - Cultural Relations Survey, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Latin American Survey - Brickell, Herschel, 1949-1953 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Latin America - Social Sciences, 300.S
    - Economics, Development of - (Fetter, Frank), 1941 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Argentina, 1917-1962; 301; 2.3 Cubic Feet; 7 __Boxes __2.3 cubic feet
  The majority of projects treated in this material are in the medical and natural sciences and date from the 1940's and 1950's. Prominent institutions are the Institute of Biochemical Research, the University of Buenos Aires, the National University of the Litoral, the Institute of Plant Science, and the University of Cordoba. Early files, generated by Foundation officers, include a report by Richard M. Pearce, "Medical Education in Argentina," (1917, 1925) and reports by Nelson C. Davis, Persis Putnum, E. R. Rickard, and R. C. Shannon.
  Eight subseries as follows:
  301 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  301 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  301 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing.
  301 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  301 I Malaria
  301 M Respiratory diseases
  301 R Humanities and arts
  301 S Social sciences
  - Institute of Biology, Buenos Aires - Equipment - (Covian, Miguel), 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rosario Health Unit, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rosario Health Unit, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Argentina - Medical Sciences, 301.A
    - Institute of Biological Research, Buenos Aires - Enzyme Chemistry - (Equipment; Lelior, Luis Federico), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Institute of Medical Research, Cordoba - De Allende, Inez - (Travel Grant), 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Institute of Medical Research, Cordoba - Equipment - (Orias, Oscar), 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Institute of Medical Research, Cordoba - Equipment - (Orias, Oscar), 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Hug, Enrique - (Visit), 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Microchemistry - (Llacer, A.J.), 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Microchemistry - (Llacer, A.J.), 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Physiology - De Meio, Humberto R., 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Physiology - Lewis, John T., 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Physiology and Pharmacology, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Physiology and Pharmacology, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Physiology and Pharmacology, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nowinski, Wiktor W. - (Medical Sciences), 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Nowinski, Wiktor W. - (Medical Sciences), 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Pea-1 Pearce,Richard and Lambert, Robert A "Medical Education in Argentina", 1917, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1941-1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Anatomy and Embryology - Reprints, 1954, 1956-1958; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Cardiology - (Taquini, Alberto C.), 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Cardiology - (Taquini, Alberto C.; Fasciolo, Juan C.), 1942-1943, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Internal Medicine - (Llanari, Alfredo), 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Microchemistry - (Sozzi, Juan), 1940, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Microchemistry - (Sozzi, Juan), 1940, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Physiology - Houssay, B.A., 1940-1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Physiology - Houssay, B.A., 1940-1946 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Physiology - Orias, Oscar, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Reca de Acosta, Telma - (Child Psychiatry), 1942-1943, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - University of Cordoba - Physiology - (Orias, Oscar), 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - University of Cordoba - Physiology - (Orias, Oscar), 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Argentina - Nursing, 301.C
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Nursing School, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - National University of the Litoral, Rosario - Nursing School, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Argentina - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 301.D
    - Asociacion Argentina para el Progresso de las Ciencias, 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Asociacion Argentina para el Progresso de las Ciencias, 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research, Buenos Aires - Cabib, Enrico, 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research, Buenos Aires - Protein Chemistry - (Paladini, Alejandro), 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Institute of Biochemical Research, Buenos Aires - Enzyme Chemistry, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Institute of Plant Science, Castelar - Vallega, Jose - (Travel Grant), 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Institute of Plant Science, Castelar - Vallega, Jose - (Travel Grant) - Report, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Institute of Plant Science, Castelar - von der Pahlen, Alejo - (Plant Virus Diseases), 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Minstry of Agriculture, Buenos Aires - Soils Institute - (Zendy-Zucker, Fr.), 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - National Astronomical Observatory, Cordoba - (Gaviola, Enrique), 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - National Astronomical Observatory, Cordoba - (Gaviola, Enrique), 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine - (Equipment and Supplies), 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Organic Chemistry - (Deulofeu, Venancio), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Organic Chemistry - (Deulofeu, Venancio), 1942-1953, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Organic Chemistry - (Deulofeu, Venancio), 1942-1953, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Organic Chemistry - (Deulofeu, Venancio), 1942-1953, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - University of Buenos Aires - Reichart, Manfredo A. L. - (Soils Science), 1954-1954 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - University of Cordoba - Biochemistry - (Marsal, Alberto), 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Argentina - Malaria, 301.I
    - (Malaria), 1919-1929, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - (Malaria), 1919-1929, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - (Malaria), 1919-1929, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 59)